His name is Zhong Man, he is a fisherman.
In fact, his cormorants fish for him.
He taught them to fetch fish.
All the fishermen do that here. But
in the area Zhong Man is a celebrity.
His birds catch the biggest fish
of the river. He trained them for that.
Every year, Zhong Man raises a small cormorant and
he wants him to be even better than the others.
For that, he needs an egg and not just any egg.
Again, Zhong Man has his little secrets.
Zhong Man has twelve cormorants, all of them male.
The eldest is called Boiteux,
He was his best fisherman for years.
Under water, he could see far. Very far.
He is the son of the lame.
Plumonge and his brother are still
like that. Zhong Man can't help it.
He is a sleeper. When he's not fishing, he's sleeping.
There is also fout camp and a dancer. They are all
able to take out eight to 10 pounds of fish per day.
But the best this year, the one that brings back the
bigger is Mao. Zhong Man decided to marry him,
To be the father of the new generation.
Mao was raised with Zhong Man's grandson.
You have to learn the language of the
cormorants. Afterwards, we no longer understand anything.
And with these birds, it is better to be obeyed very early.
Mao and the child, play, eat and sleep together,
Since their birth. Zhong Man was also brought up like this.
Mao is the descendant of a large cormorant family.
Cormorant fishing is a tradition as old as China.
Formerly, it was the emperor himself
who gave us permission.
Today, it is enough to be called Wang.
All the cormorant fishermen are called Wang.
Whenever Zhong Man is looking for a female, he comes to see Wang Zindzi. As he is no longer old enough to fish, he marries cormorants.
Among cormorants, fleeting adventures lead to nothing.
The eggs never open. Only weddings
of love make beautiful children.
For Zhong Man, the female who will please
Mao, will be gentle and very enterprising.
Cormorants can stay two minutes under
water and dive up to 25 meters deep.
Instinctively, Mao knows where the fish are
hide and Zhong Man trusts him.
Sometimes a cormorant wanders off and gets lost.
But the cormorants always return where
they were born and those there were born at Zhong Man.
Cormorants eat part of the peach.
The family, another, and the rest is sold.
Here are two females from a good family. For Mahaut, she
should please him. Now it's up to him to choose.
With cormorants, it's pretty quick.
And the one who is not chosen does not make a fuss.
This female is called Princess Celeste.
She will surely give a lot of pleasure to this young king.
For lovers, Zhong Man has prepared
a house out of sight.
In five days he will have eggs.
Mao will stay with his princess as long as he pleases.
Zhong Man says it's the custom.
That he'll come back when he's had enough.
But not everyone agrees with this custom.
Cormorants make their nest in a few hours
with what they find at the bottom of the river.
Everyone has their role. Mao is working and Princess Celeste is watching.
Every hour, Zhong Man leaves his
birds to rest and dry off a bit.
Fishing sometimes lasts all night, sometimes even until morning.
Eggs are not all viable.
But Zhong Man knows how to recognize the good seed.
It can even recognize males from females.
For these wild birds to get used to
man, they must be born near man.
Zhong Man removes the eggs from the nest very early to entrust them to a hen, preferably lazy, and who is already incubating hers.
The hen covers a Mao egg for 25 days.
Zhong Man does not like to wait and every year he leaves
away, looking for new fishing spots.
In the villages where he fishes, he must
give away half of his catch.
We don't know why the fish all congregate
the years at that time where the river is deep.
All fishermen also come with their birds.
Zhong Man must go home now.
He must be there for the hatching of his egg.
If the hen notices the deception, she can
attack the hatchling when it comes out of the egg.
Zhong Man removes the eggs 10 hours before hatching.
He must keep them at the right temperature.
Thus begins for Zhong Man a long
standby period which will last two months.
Two months during which it will be necessary to nourish
the little cormorant every hour,
And make sure he doesn't catch hot or cold.
The first eight days, Zhong Man does not want anyone near the baby.
He does not leave him.
He doesn't sleep, he can't sleep.
It won't be out for a week.
As soon as he can walk, he will follow Zhong Man
and hide in his boots.
In two months, he will accompany the big
on the boat. He will watch them do it.
In two years, he will be a great fisherman.
For 20 years he will fish for Zhong Man
and if he is strong, we will marry him off.
And when he is too old, Zhong Man will make him
drink rice wine so that it goes away smoothly.
There you go, Zhong Man's family lives like
it since the first millennium.
There is no reason for that to change.